Joshua Reynolds Collection
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
Joshua Reynolds Archive
1749-1816
MSS.30
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
1
The collection comprises correspondence, notebooks, writings, and other manuscript material by or about the artist Joshua Reynolds.
Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792
Hilles, Frederick W. (Frederick Whiley), 1900-1975
Hope, Henry, 1735 or 1736-1811
Jansen, Hendrik, 1741-1812
Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784
Montagu, Mrs. (Elizabeth), 1718-1800
Rutland, Charles Manners, Duke of, 1754-1787
West, Benjamin, 1738-1820
Yver, P. (Pieter), 1712-1787
Existence and Location of Copies
Letters by Reynolds have been published by Hilles and Ingamells/Edgcumbe, as noted in the Bibliography herewith. Material in the present collection described in Ingamells has been annotated with the Ingamells entry number.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series: I. Correspondence; II. Commonplace books, notebooks, and diaries; III. Writings; and IV. Miscellaneous.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Frederick W. Hilles.
Related Materials
Additional material from the Hilles collection of Reynolds material is now in the Department of Prints and Drawings at the Yale Center for British Art. Records for this material may be accessed in the YCBA's online catalog: http://http://britishart.yale.edu/collections/search
A portion of the Hilles collection of Reynolds material is now at the Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library (Yale University), in the Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.hilles.
Frederick W. Hilles' copy of his Letters of Sir Joshua Reynolds (Cambridge, 1929), with his profuse annotations, is now in the collections of the Yale Center for British Art: http://hdl.handle.net/10079/bibid/582640.
Biographical / Historical
"There has never been a time when Joshua Reynolds was not regarded as one of the great men of the Enlightenment in England and a portrait and history painter of tremendous versatility, inventiveness, originality, and ambition.
Reynolds was the seventh of the ten or eleven children of a schoolmaster and his wife, both of whose families were abundant with Church of England clergymen. Showing prodigious talent as a boy, he was apprenticed for four years to the London portrait painter Thomas Hudson of Lincoln's Inn Fields, before establishing a burgeoning portrait practice in London and Plymouth. In 1749-50, Reynolds traveled to Italy and France by way of Spain and Morocco. In Rome he copied the Old Masters, for eighteen months scouring the city's churches' princely art collections and working his way back across the Continent, similarly absorbing a host of artistic exempla. Upon his return to London, Reynolds resumed his portrait practice and achieved rapid commercial and critical success, although the failure of some of his experiments with certain fugitive pigments and varnishes was soon apparent.
Beginning in 1760, when he leased a large house at 47 Leicester Square, Reynolds exhibited with the Society of Artists but eventually distanced himself from the squabbles that increasingly divided the members from their committee. He also hesitated before accepting the invitation to become the first President of a rival "Academy" that was founded in 1768 with patronage of King George III. As President, Reynolds was knighted in April 1769, an honor that was not without precedent but that signaled Reynolds's certain preeminence in the institutional art world of London. In the Discourses he delivered as President, Reynolds set out the principles to which a great national school of art should adhere, ennobled by poetry and eloquence, intellectual dignity, and the purity of the so-called great style of Michelangelo, Raphael, and the Florentine-Roman tradition of disegno.
In the 1770s and 1780s, Reynolds's portrait subjects included most of the great men and women of the age: his own good friend Dr. Samuel Johnson, the king and queen, Sir Joseph Banks, James Boswell, Oliver Goldsmith, David Garrick, and others. He created a sideline in imaginative portrait studies of children, known as "fancy pictures," and also experimented with history painting. As Reynolds aged, he showed an increasing awareness of and interest in Dutch art and continued to be showered with honors, both domestic and foreign. In old age, the deafness he blamed on a chill he said he caught in the Sistine Chapel got worse (but that, like his harelip, was probably hereditary); in addition, his eyesight deteriorated. Although he was immensely self-important, and to that extent personally vain, in his marvelous self-portraits Reynolds freely acknowledged the existence of all three maladies, most obviously the harelip, but also his ear trumpet and spectacles, while other artists in their portraits of him rarely acknowledged their existence. After his death in 1792, Reynolds's body was attended by ten pallbearers, among whom were three dukes, two marquesses, three earls, and a cortègee of ninety-one carriages."--Paul Mellon's Legacy (2007).
Frederick Whiley Hilles (1900-1975) was a longtime professor of English at Yale University and editor of works on Samuel Johnson, James Boswell, and Joshua Reynolds. Hilles collected correspondence and other manuscript writings by James Boswell, Thomas Carlyle, Samuel Johnson, Joshua Reynolds, and members of their families. Most of this material is now at the Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library (Yale University), in the Frederick W. Hilles Manuscript Collection (http://hdl.handle.net/10079/fa/beinecke.hilles). Hilles's Reynolds collection was featured (along with material from other collections) in An exhibition of books, manuscripts & prints pertaining to Sir Joshua Reynolds, on the two hundred and fiftieth anniversary of his birth (Beinecke Rare Book & Manuscript Library, 1973). A portion of Hilles's Reynolds material now forms the present collection at the Yale Center for British Art.
Scope and Contents
The collection comprises correspondence, notebooks, writings, and other manuscript material by or about the artist Joshua Reynolds. Correspondents include Francis Barton Abington, Carl Fredrik Adelcrantz, John Bacon, Joseph Banks, Edmund Burke, Sir William Hamilton, John Hely-Hutchinson, Henry Hope, Hendrik Jansen, Samuel Johnson, William Johnson, Bennet Langton, Elizabeth Montagu, Thomas Percy, William Roscoe, Charles Manners, Duke of Rutland, Richard Brinsley Sheridan, F.G. Waldron, Benjamin West, and Pieter Yver. Several of the notebooks record Reynolds's travels on the Continent, with notes on paintings seen in France, Germany, and the Low Countries. Among the writings are Reynolds's thoughts on blindness, fragments of his Discourses, and notes on Pliny and Johnson. Some of the material throughout the collection concerns Reynolds's tenure as the first president of the Royal Academy.
Bibliography
Reynolds, Joshua. Letters of Sir Joshua Reynolds collected and edited by Frederick Whiley Hilles. Cambridge (England): University Press, 1929.
Reynolds, Joshua. The letters of Sir Joshua Reynolds, edited by John Ingamells and John Edgcumbe. New Haven: Yale University Press for the Paul Mellon Centre for Studies in British Art, 2000.
Wendorf, Richard. Sir Joshua Reynolds: the painter in society. Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard University Press, 1996
Yale University Library. An exhibition of books, manuscripts & prints pertaining to Sir Joshua Reynolds. New Haven: Yale University Library, 1973.
Painting, European; Antwerp (Belgium) -- Description and travel; Belgium -- Description and travel; Brussels (Belgium) -- Description and travel; Germany -- Description and travel; Netherlands -- Description and travel; Paris (France) -- Description and travel; Rotterdam (Netherlands) -- Description and travel; Commonplace books; Diaries; Letters; Notebooks; Catherine, Empress of Russia, II, 1729-1796 -- Art collections; Abington, Mrs. (Frances Barton), 1737-1815 -- Correspondence; Adelcrantz, Carl Fredrik, 1716-1796 -- Correspondence; Bacon, John, 1740-1799 -- Correspondence; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820 -- Correspondence; Beaumont, George Howland, Sir, 1753-1827; Breda, C. F. von (Carl Fredrik), 1759-1818; Burke, Edmund, 1729-1797 -- Correspondence; Burke, Jane Mary Nugent, 1734-1812; Doughty, William, 1757-1780 or 1782; Dufresnoy, Charles-Alphonse, 1611-1668; Gainsborough, Thomas, 1727-1788; Gwatkin, Theophila Palmer, 1757-1848; Hamilton, William, 1751-1801 -- Correspondence; Haughton, Moses, 1773-1849; Hely-Hutchinson, John, 1724-1794 -- Correspondence; Hope, Henry, 1735 or 1736-1811 -- Correspondence; Hudson, Thomas, 1701-1779; Jansen, Hendrik, 1741-1812 -- Correspondence; Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784 ( Correspondence); Johnson, William, d. 1779 -- Correspondence; Langton, Bennet, 1737-1801 -- Correspondence; Mason, William, 1725-1797; Meyer, Henry Hoppner, 1783-1847; Meyer, Jeremiah, 1735-1789; Milton, John, 1608-1674; Montagu, Mrs. (Elizabeth), 1718-1800 -- Correspondence; Palmer, Joseph, 1749-1829; Percy, Thomas, 1729-1811 ( Correspondence); Pope, Alexander, 1688-1744; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 ( Correspondence); Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Diaries; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Notebooks, sketchbooks, etc.; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 ( Discourses); Roscoe, William, 1753-1831 -- Correspondence; Rubens, Peter Paul, 1577-1640; Rutland, Charles Manners, Duke of, 1754-1787 -- Correspondence; Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616; Sheridan, Elizabeth Ann, 1754-1792; Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1751-1816 -- Correspondence; Tarleton, Lieutenant-General (Banastre), 1754-1833; Titian, approximately 1488-1576; Upper Ossory, Anne Fitzpatrick, Countess of, 1737 or 8-1804 -- Correspondence; Upper Ossory, John Fitzpatrick, Earl of, 1745-1818; Waldron, F. G. (Francis Godolphin), 1744-1818 -- Correspondence; West, Benjamin, 1738-1820 -- Correspondence; Yver, P. (Pieter), 1712-1787 -- Correspondence; Royal Academy of Arts (Great Britain)
- Correspondence, Series I
  - Letter to Miss Weston, 1749 December 10; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 3 pages; 22 x 16 cm. (Box Reynolds 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Written from Port Mahon, Minorca. Concerning his voyage to Italy. Ingamells no. 5.
    Italy -- Description and travel; Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Weston (Miss) -- Correspondence
  - Letter to the Honorable William Hamilton at Naples, 1769 March 28; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 3 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 2)
    Regarding the establishment of the Royal Academy, of which Sir Joshua Reynolds has the honor of being president. Ingamells no. 21.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Royal Academy of Arts (Great Britain); Hamilton, William, Sir, 1730-1803 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Frances Abington at Pallmall, between 1769 and 1777? May 26; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 1 page; 20 x 17 cm. (Box Reynolds 3)
    Accepting an invitation. Ingamells no. 231.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Abington, Mrs. (Francis Barton), 1737-1815 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Sir Joshua Reynolds and his nieces, 1777 January 4; Montagu, Mrs. (Elizabeth), 1718-1800; 1 page; 7 x 10 cm. (Box Reynolds 4)
    Written from Hill Street. Dinner invitation for 7 January 1777.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Montagu, Mrs. (Elizabeth), 1718-1800 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to the Reverend Thomas Percy, 1777 March 5; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 1 page; 19 x 16 cm. (Box Reynolds 5)
    Requesting Thomas Percy's aid on behalf of a relative of Jane [Mrs. Edmund] Burke. Ingamells no. 60.
    Correspondence; Percy, Thomas, 1729-1811 -- Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Burke, Jane Mary Nugent, 1734-1812
  - Letter to John Hely-Hutchinson, 1780; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 2 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 6)
    Addressed to the Secretary of State in Ireland. Letter of recommendation for a young painter, William Doughty, a pupil of Reynolds, who wishes to spend a few months in Ireland. Ingamells no. 90.
    Correspondence; Doughty, William, 1757-1780 or 2; Hely-Hutchinson, John, 1724-1794 -- Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Sir Joshua Reynolds, [1778] August 14; Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784; 1 page; 8 x 11 cm. (Box Reynolds 7)
    Sending him, presumably, his lives of Denham, Butler, and Waller, specially bound to be read by friends.
    Correspondence; Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784 -- Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to William Johnson, 1780; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 4 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 8)
    Apologizing to his nephew for his tardiness in writing, and wishing him success in India. Ingamells no. 91.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Johnson, William, d. 1779 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Edmund Burke, 1781 August 10; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 4 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 9)
    Written from Rotterdam. Includes impression of paintings by Rubens, with description of Rotterdam and surrounding countryside. Ingamells no. 95.
    Rotterdam (Netherlands) -- Description and travel; Correspondence; Burke, Edmund, 1729-1797 -- Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Rubens, Peter Paul, 1577-1640
  - Letter to Sir Joshua Reynolds at London, 1781 October 2; Yver, P. (Pieter), 1712-1787; 3 pages; 24 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 10)
    Written from Amsterdam. An agent in Amsterdam, Yver, reports to Sir Joshua Reynolds on certain paintings he has purchased for him. Signed Pierre Yver.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Yver, P. (Pieter), 1712-1787 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Sir Joshua Reynolds, 1781 October 5; Hope, Henry, 1735 or 6-1811; 3 pages; 24 x 20 cm. (Box Reynolds 11)
    Written from Amsterdam. Concerning the shipping of pictures purchased for Sir Joshua Reynolds by Pieter Yver.
    Correspondence; Hope, Henry, 1735 or 6-1811 -- Correspondence; Yver, P. (Pieter), 1712-1787; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to William Johnson, 1783 January 19; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 2 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 12)
    Written from London. Introducing the young artist, Mr. Meyer, and mentioning the "violent inflammation in his [own] eye." Notes Miss Theophila Palmer's marriage to Robert Gwatkin. Ingamells no. 108.
    Correspondence; Meyer, Jeremiah, 1735-1789; Johnson, William, d. 1779 -- Correspondence; Gwatkin, Theophila Palmer, 1757-1848; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Sir Joshua Reynolds, 1783 February 19; Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784; 2 pages; 26 x 21 cm. (Box Reynolds 13)
    Thanking him for Mason's translation of du Fresnoy and sending him the new edition of his The Lives of the Poets, just published. A presentation inscription from R. B. Adam, a former owner, to R. W. Chapman is written on the mount surrounding the letter. A copy of the pamphlet by R. W. Chapman, entitled The lives of the poets: Sir Joshua Reynolds's copy of the first edition, sent to him by Johnson 19 February 1783, 1929, is affixed to the back of the mount. Another copy of the pamphlet is affixed to the case. With the letter is cased: Gwatkin, R. G. ALS to R. W. Chapman. Oxford, January 13 [1930?].
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784 -- Correspondence; Mason, William, 1725-1797; Dufresnoy, Charles-Alphonse, 1611-1668
  - Letter to Sir Joshua Reynolds, 1784 September 16; Rutland, Charles Manners, Duke of, 1754-1787; 3 pages; 24 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 14)
    Hoping to promote Joseph Palmer, Sir Joshua Reynolds' nephew. Congratulating Sir Joshua on his new appointment as principal painter to the King.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Palmer, Joseph, 1749-1829; Rutland, Charles Manners, Duke of, 1754-1787 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to William Roscoe, 1784 October 16; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 1 page; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 15)
    Referring to the portrait of Colonel Tarleton. Ingamells no. 127.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Roscoe, William, 1753-1831 -- Correspondence; Tarleton, Lieutenant-General (Banastre), 1754-1833
  - Letter to Cunynham at Lille, 1785 November 25; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 3 pages; 24 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 16)
    Written from London. Concerning two paintings by Rubens which Reynolds wishes to buy. Addressed to "Monsieur Cunynham, at Lille." Ingamells no. 146. Ingamells identifies the recipient as possibly William Burton Conyngham (1733-1796); previously identified as Edmund Francis Cunningham.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Rubens, Peter Paul, 1577-1640; Conyngham, William Burton, 1732 or 3-1796 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Francis Godolphin Waldron, 1785 November 5; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 1 page; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 17)
    Written from Leicester Fields. Concerning a picture of Milton. "Sir Joshua Reynolds presents his compliments to Mr. Waldron..." Ingamells no. 145.
    Correspondence; Milton, John, 1608-1674; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Waldron, F. G. (Francis Godolphin), 1744-1818 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to the Earl of Upper Ossory, 1786 July 10; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 3 pages; 24 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 18)
    Written from London. Offering to trade Gainsborough's "Girl with Pigs" for a damaged "Venus and Adonis" copied by Titian. Ingamells no. 153.
    Correspondence; Upper Ossory, John Fitzpatrick, Earl of, 1745-1818 -- Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Gainsborough, Thomas, 1727-1788; Titian, circa 1488-1576
  - Letter to Sir George Beaumont at Tunbridge Wells, 1786 August 23; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 2 pages; 30 x 21 cm. (Box Reynolds 19)
    Written from London. Hastily telling him of paintings to see while in the Low Countries. Ingamells no. 156.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Beaumont, George Howland, Sir, 1753-1827 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Henri Jansen, 1786 October 2; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 3 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 20a)
    Written from London. Sending Jansen "all the Discourses since the year 1776." Expressing his appreciation for Jansen's translation of his Discourses into French. Ingamells no. 161.
    On same sheet as Reynolds 20b: Jansen's letter to Reynolds from Paris, October 10, 1786.
    Correspondence; Jansen, Hendrik, 1741-1812 -- Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Sir Joshua Reynolds, 1786 October 10; Jansen, Hendrik, 1741-1812; 2 pages; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 20b)
    First draft (?) of Jansen's response to Reynolds' letter of October 2, 1786. Written on same sheet as Reynolds 20a.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Jansen, Hendrik, 1741-1812 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Henri Jansen, 1787 January 10; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 1 page; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 21)
    Sending him a copy of the thirteenth Discourse, just published. Jansen was translating the Discourses into French. Ingamells no. 167.
  - [no item] (Box Reynolds 22)
  - Letter to Bennet Langton, 1787 August 31; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 1 page; 21 x 17 cm. (Box Reynolds 23)
    Sending him a present in pottles for the Langton children. Ingamells no. 174.
    Correspondence; Langton, Bennet, 1737-1801 -- Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Joseph Palmer, 1787 December 7; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 3 pages; 24 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 24)
    Offering condolences on the death of Palmer's patron, the Duke of Rutland, and giving further advice on the subject of patrons. Ingamells no. 179.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Rutland, Charles Manners, Duke of, 1754-1787; Palmer, Joseph, 1749-1829 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Richard Brinsley Sheridan, 1790 January 20; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 3 pages; 24 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 25)
    Presenting to him the portrait of Mrs. Sheridan as St. Cecilia, "the best picture I ever painted." Ingamells no. 191.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1751-1816 -- Correspondence; Sheridan, Elizabeth Ann, 1754-1792
  - Letter to Mrs. ?, 1929 July; Sheridan, A. B.; 1 page; 17 x 13 cm. (Box Reynolds 26)
    Written from Frampton Court, Dorchester. Presenting the letter written by Sir Joshua Reynolds to Richard Brinsley Sheridan, January 20, 1790.
    Correspondence; Sheridan, A. B. -- Correspondence; Sheridan, Richard Brinsley, 1751-1816 -- Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792
  - Letter to John Bacon, 1790 January; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 2 pages; 20 x 16 cm. (Box Reynolds 27)
    A note concerning the quarrel that led to Sir Joshua Reynolds' resignation from the Royal Academy. Ingamells no. 192.
    Correspondence; Royal Academy of Arts (Great Britain); Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Bacon, John, 1740-1799 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Bishop Percy, 1790 March 13; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 1 page; 30 x 24 cm. (Box Reynolds 28)
    Written from Leicester Fields. A brief note accompanying Boswell's letter of the day before, mentioning his failing eyesight. Verso: Clipping of a short biography of Reynolds. With a stipple engraving of Reynolds by H. Meyer, after M. Haughton (from the original painted by Reynolds himself). Ingamells no. 198.
    Engravings; Correspondence; Meyer, Henry, 1782?-1847; Haughton, Moses, 1773-1849; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Percy, Thomas, 1729-1811 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Mr. West, [1790] April 8; West, Benjamin, 1738-1820; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 1 page; 23 x 19 cm. (Box Reynolds 29)
    Offering to send his coach if West wishes to accompany him to see the drawings in the collection of Mr. Hankey. Ingamells no. 200.
    Verso: graphite sketch by West (23 x 26 cm).
    Correspondence; Graphite drawings; Hankey, Thomas, d. 1793; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; West, Benjamin, 1738-1820 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to the Countess of Ossory, 1791 January 1; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 2 pages; 24 x 20 cm. (Box Reynolds 30)
    Letter of thanks for the hand-embroidered waistcoat. Ingamells no. 211.
    Correspondence; Clothing and dress; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Upper Ossory, Anne Fitzpatrick, Countess of, 1737 or 8-1804 -- Correspondence
  - Letter to Sir Joseph Banks, Bart, 1791 March 15; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; 1 page; 20 x 17 cm. (Box Reynolds 31)
    Asking him as chairman of the committee to call a meeting concerning the monument to be erected to Dr. Johnson. Ingamells no. 215.
    Correspondence; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820 -- Correspondence; Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784
  - Letter to Sir Joshua Reynolds, 1791 May 10; Adelcrantz, Carl Fredrik, 1716-1796; 3 pages; 20 x 17 cm. (Box Reynolds 32)
    Written from Stockholm. Requesting that de Breda, now in London, be permitted to paint for the Swedish Academy a portrait of Sir Joshua Reynolds, "the most celebrated artist of this century."
    Correspondence; Breda, C. F. von (Carl Fredrik), 1759-1818; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792 -- Correspondence; Adelcrantz, Carl Fredrik, 1716-1796 -- Correspondence